Sintayehu Mekonnen

sintemite@gmail.com

https://sintu.ga

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sintayehu-mekonnen-35b88716a/ (404) 935-2192

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

I am an energetic, well-trained Web Developer who knows how to create, design, and modify web content.

I am a results-driven individual with the capacity to adapt and learn fast. I have proven skills in web development including knowledge of HTML, CSS, JavaScript. I have excellent communication skills and am able to multi-task in a fast-paced environment. I am an outstanding and conscientious team player, who is willing to learn new skills. I possess a positive attitude and have experience working in diverse environments.

EDUCATION

Georgia Piedmont Technical College, Clarkston, GA

Associate Degree in Applied Science: Computer Support Specialist (2018) Help Desk Specialist Certificate (April 2018) PC Repair and Network Technician Certificate (July 2017) CompTIA A+ Certified Technician Preparation Certificate (Dec 2017)

Udemy

Web Developer Bootcamp Certificate (March 2018) AngularJS Certificate (Nov 2017) Node JS Certificate (Nov 2017) Build a Real Time web app Certificate (Nov 2017)

Friends of Refugees

Web Development Certificate (August 2017)

Ethiopian Civil Service University

Transformational Leadership Development and Decision-Making Certificate (December 2013)

SKILLS

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- jQuery
- Bootstrap
- Cross-browser development
- Git
- GitHub
- Chrome Inspector

- Coding tools
- Debugging tools
- FTP
- Web Hosting
- Knowledge about computer hardware and software
- Troubleshooting
- Operating System

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web Developer and IT Consultant Clarkston, GA 2016 - present

- Developed websites using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript (Sample: https://sintu.ga)
- Created responsive web sites
- Utilized creative and analytical problem-solving and troubleshooting skills
- Troubleshoot personal, family and friend's computers
- Installed and configured software
- Network peripheral devices

Customer Service Rep/Cashier Dekalb Farmers Market – Decatur, GA 2015 –2017

- Exhibited professionalism and effective verbal and written communication skills to enhance customer experience
- Provided information on procedures or policies
- Calculated total payments received and reconciled this with total sales
- Performed quick math calculations when collecting payments
- Updated customer information in the customer service database

Regional Relation Officer Communication Affairs – Ethiopia 2009 – 2015

- Documented customers' information in the computer
- Maintained and updated information on the organization's website
- Created and modified tables; entered and maintained data in the database
- Assisted in the development of plans and report formation
- Analyzed and evaluated the function of agencies and organizations and their impact on international relations